I never dreamed before
I'm gonna knock the door
into the world of perfect free
(You ain't no lonely!)
You're gonna say I'm lying
I'm gonna get the chance
I thought a chance is far from me
(You ain't no lonely!)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
You are the sun, you are the star
(To me, forever)
I was made to hit in America
(I was made to hit in America)
Sorrow is what I hate
but it's grown my sensations.
Regrets taught me how
to make any hard decisions.
Peace is always by my side
but I've never felt it once.
Love is not the word only
for the sweet romance.
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
Well, I didn't expect this.
（レオン：英語）〈まさか
こんな展開になるとはな〉
It's Malcolm's fault.
（ゴールディー：英語）
〈マルコムのせいですよ〉
That punk from Newark.
〈ニューアークの若僧め！〉
He just went back to the hotel
without saying anything.
〈勝手にホテルに
帰りやがって!!〉
There are plenty of Mongolian Chop squads.
On this planet...
（レオン）〈モンゴリアン・
チョップ・スクワッドは—〉
〈世の中に掃いて捨てるほどいる〉
...they're one of those shitty
bands that don't make no money.
〈金にならないクズバンドの
１つにしか過ぎない〉
They fucking suck.
I saw the letter from
Uncle Davis by accident.
（ゴールディー）
〈デイビス叔父の手紙—〉
〈ちょっと見ちゃったんですけど〉
I can't believe what I read.
〈“サニーボーイの伝説を継ぐ男
リュースケ・ミナミへ”って〉
It said, "To Ryusuke Minami...
The man who will inherit
the legend of Sonny Boy."
〈書いてありましたね〉
My uncle says that to everybody.
〈叔父は 誰にでもそう言うんだ〉
What?
〈はぁ〉
But it is the first time he says
（レオン）〈だが ルシールを
ゆずると言ったのは—〉
he actually is gonna hand
over the Lucille to them.
That's a first.
〈今回が初めてだ〉
Recalling my torn broken,
aching heart of these long days.
And all the memories I wanted
to forget for making leaps.
Recalling, breaking, aching, crying,
making sure to me.
And I take all and grin
at my future on the way.
Sorrow is what I hate
but it's grown my sensations.
Regrets taught me how
to make any hard decisions.
Peace is always by my side
but I've never felt it once.
So that's how they get the audience.
（レオン）
〈オーディエンスを集めるわけだ〉
Peace is always by my side
but I've never felt it once.
Boss, that little bastard...
（ゴールディー）
〈ボス あの小僧…〉
Love is not the word
only for the sweet romance. Yeah.
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
And I'm scared to keep on
going on my way. Yeah.
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
Huh? What's up?
（男性）あ… どうした？
知ってる曲？
Well I'm scared, I'm scared,
I'm scared, I'm scared to death.
-You know this song?
-It's the first time I'm hearing it...
（泉(いずみ)）初めて聞いたけど—
And I'll tell myself
I'm special till the end.
-But it's a really great song.
-Yeah.
すごく いい歌ね
And I'll tell myself
I'm special till the end.
（力也(りきや)）ウォー！
Wow!
（マリア）ワーオ
Koyuki-kun...Saku-chan...
（益岡(ますおか)）
コユキ君… サクちゃん…
I don't give my heart to no one
cause I don't wanna waste my time.
Koyuki-kun...Saku-chan...
I don't give my heart to no one
cause I don't wanna waste my time.
I tried to love this loneliness
to slip out of lonesome hole.
（観客たち）
アンコール！ アンコール！
Hey, do you hear that?
（千葉(ちば)）おい 聞こえるか？
They're calling for us!
マジに 俺たちを呼んでるんだ
（竜介(りゅうすけ)）ハァ ハァ ハァ…
（平(たいら)）ハァ ハァ…
（サク）結果的には
すごいライブだったよね
It turned out to be...
an awesome live.
But Koyuki is amazing.
（平）
しかし コユキはすごいぜ
He went up on stage all alone.
１人でステージに
上がっちまうんだからな
I couldn't have done that.
（平）俺には なかったよ
そんな勇気…
-I'm not that brave.
-All of you...All of you came.
（コユキ）みんなが…
みんなが来てくれて…
That's why I could do it.
だから できたんだ
I wouldn't have had such a
great time all by myself.
俺１人の力じゃ
こんなに楽しめなかったと思う
Alright! Let's do an encore!
（千葉）
じゃあ アンコールいくぞ！
Are you okay, Koyuki?
（サク）大丈夫か？ コユキ
Uh-huh...
But can I take three minutes to rest?
３分 休んでもいいかな？
Hey, are you gonna
keep your audience waiting?!
（千葉）おい！ オーディエンスを
待たせるつもりか？
（竜介）ふんっ！
Koyuki's too exhausted.
Let him rest.
コユキは無理だ 休ましてやれ
Hey, Ryusuke...
おい 竜介…
I'm outta here.
（竜介）俺は 消える
I thought this time
we'd have a permanent band.
今度はパーマネントなバンドだと
思ったんだけどな
Ryusuke-kun!
（コユキ）竜介君～！
ハァ ハァ…
Yo, what's up, Koyuki?
おう どうした？ コユキ
ハァ ハァ… ぬあっ！
-Ahh...
-Hey!
（竜介）おい！
ほらほら 危ねえじゃねえか
You see? Watch out!
You're exhausted.
お前は疲れてるんだ
今は無理すんな
Don't force yourself.
You okay?
大丈夫か？
I wanted to tell you...
（コユキ）言いたくて
ハァ…
Ryusuke-kun...Thank you.
竜介君 ありがとう
Be seeing you, Koyuki.
じゃあな コユキ
（学(まなぶ)）お～ 花火だ！ しみるぜ！
Wow! Fireworks! How touching!
Huh, Eiji-kun?
ねえ？ 栄二(えいじ)君
（栄二）ハァ ハァ…
Huh?
Yoshito...you...
（学）ヨシト お前…
Maho won't answer.
（ヨシト）真帆(まほ)が出ないんだ
Main stage, 8,900 people.
（和緒(かずお)）メインステージ 8,900人
セカンドステージ 980人
Second Stage, 980 people.
And Third Stage, 8,100 people...
そして
サードステージ 8,100人
and growing steadily!
今も移動してる客 多数
It's unbelievable,
（和緒）信じられないけど—
but if this keeps up,
Stage 3 will turn it around and win.
このままいけば
サードステージの大逆転勝利ね
メインステージの観客は
減る一方だし—
The main stage keeps
losing spectators...
and I don't see
the crowd lessening.
サードステージに向かう人の流れは
全然 止まらないもん
But we've got trouble on Stage 3.
（付き人）
そのサードステージなんですが—
大混乱ですよ
人数は驚異的に増えてますが—
The crowd has grown tremendously,
but BECK hasn't
come back for an encore.
BECK(ベック)のメンバー
アンコールをしないみたいなんです
Huh? Why?!
え？ 何でよ？
Well, I...
（付き人）
え… それは… うわっ！
Encore! BECK! BECK!
（男性客）アンコール！
（男性客たち）BECK！ BECKー！
（女性客）出てきてー！
（男性客１）聞かしてくれー!
-Come out!
-Give us an encore!
（男性客２）アンコール！
（観客たち）
アンコール！ アンコール！
-Encore! Encore!
-Hey, that's...
（男性客１）あ？ あれって？
（女性客１）ウッソ～
-Encore! Encore!
-No way!
（男性客２）
あ BECKのボーカルだ！
It's the vocalist for BECK!
（男性客２）あ 逃げた！
（男性客２）おい 待てよ！
（女性客２）待って！
-Hey, he's running away! Hey! Wait!
-Wait! Wait!
（男性客２）おーい 待てよ！
（女性客２）ちょっと！
真帆！
（南 真帆）ヘヘッ 行くよ！
Maho!
Let's go!
真帆！
Maho!
うっ！
（真帆）コユキ！
-Koyuki!
-Maho!
真帆！
（真帆）誰も ついてこれないね
No one can follow us!
No!
（真帆）コユキ 速すぎるよ
Koyuki, you're too fast!
You were watching?
（コユキ）見ててくれたんだ？
Uh-huh.
（真帆）だってさ コユキ…
After all, Koyuki...
Koyuki...
コユキ…
コユキ すごいライブだったよ
That was an awesome performance.
Seriously, I was blown away.
マジ 感動した
コユキ すごく
かっこいいんだもん
Koyuki...you're so cool.
（コユキ）
これが 最後のライブだよ
This is gonna be our final live.
Are you sure?
（真帆）アー ユー シュア？
Yeah.
（コユキ）
次の日もステージでは—
The next day, many great
bands performed on stage.
すげえライブが
ドカドカ 爆音を立てていた
（平）おい コユキ 早くしろって
Hey, Koyuki...Hurry it up.
Uh-huh.
千葉君は？
Where's Chiba-kun?
（平）あいつは電車で帰るってさ
He's going home by train.
（コユキ）へえ～
Oh...
（サク）
１人になりたいんだってさ
He said he wants to be alone.
（女性客１）あのさ
きのうのライブ—
I heard that a band named
BECK was great yesterday.
BECKってバンドが
すごかったんだって
（女性客２）へえ～
Oh yeah?
（女性客１）見たかった～ 超！
（コユキ）ん？
I really, really wanted to see that.
コユキ？
Koyuki!
Oh, sorry!
ああ！ ゴメン ゴメン！
（コユキ）
あしたも あさっても—
Tomorrow and the day after
and the day after that...Time will pass.
日常は淡々と過ぎていくんだ
Regardless of what happens to BECK.
たとえ
BECKが どうなろうと…
（コユキ）サク これ見てよ！
Saku, take a look at this.
（サク）わー！ すごいね！
Wow! Awesome!
（コユキ）あのライブから
もう１か月半…
A month and a half has passed
since that live performance.
俺 何してんだろう
What am I doing?
（コユキの母）幸雄 電話よ！
Yukio, telephone!
誰？
Who is it?
（コユキの母）
佐藤っていう女の人！
Some lady named Sato.
イッ イテテ…
O-Ouch!
（和緒）コユキ君？
Koyuki-kun, do you have some
time tomorrow afternoon?
あしたの昼ごろなんだけど
時間ある？
え？ あした？
Huh? Tomorrow?
（和緒）
駅前の犬のところに13時ね
In front of the station
by that dog. At one p.m.
（和緒）BECKのライブは
すでに伝説になってんのよ
BECK's live performance
has become a legend.
Oh...
（コユキ）はぁ… あ 雑誌に…
-I saw the magazine.
-Lots of things are being said,
（和緒）いろんなこと
言われてるけど—
あの混乱じゃ
正確な数を出すのは不可能ね
but it's impossible to get a true count
from that huge mass of people.
（コユキ）
きょうは どうして俺を？
Why did you want to see me?
君に会いたいって人がいてさ
フフッ…
There's someone
who wants to meet you.
（コユキ）それって 誰？
Who is it?
きっと驚くわよ フフフ…
You'll be shocked.
（レオン）
〈ようこそ ユキオ〉
Welcome, Yukio.
〈さっそく話の本題に入ろう〉
Let me get straight
to the point today.
〈私は君を全米でソロデビュー
させたいと思っている〉
I'd like to talk about your
solo debut in the United States.
（コユキ）え… これって…
Uh...Is this...
（和緒）彼は
ミスター レオン・サイクス
He's Mr. Leon Sykes.
コユキ君を—
He wants you to make
a solo debut across America.
全米でソロデビュー
させたいそうよ
Don't you mess with me baby.
Everybody knows I'm here.
All I've got to say, yeah,
got my mind made up.
This is a great guitar.
（コユキ）いいギターですね
I'll let you think about it.
〈結論を急ぐ必要はない〉
Great, man!
（ゴールディー）〈グレート！〉
（レオン）
〈これから何度も会って—〉
We'll meet over and over again
to talk about this project.
〈このプロジェクトについて
話し合おう〉
We released five gold discs
from RJ Label last year.
〈昨年 我々の
ＲＪレーベルから—〉
〈８枚のゴールドディスクを
出している〉
Wow! Malcolm and Fat Jimmy
and Danger Soul!
マルコムにファット&amp;ジミー&amp;
デンジャー・ソウル！
They're all at the top
of the charts right now!
今 チャートをにぎわしてる人たち
ばっかりじゃない！
I'm sorry.
I can't accept your proposal.
（コユキ）ごめんなさい
この話は お受けできません
I'm returning the guitar, too.
ギターも お返しします
What?!
（レオン）ホワット？
H-Hey Koyuki-kun!
（和緒）
ちょ… ちょっと コユキ君！
（佐藤：英語）
〈とにかく また電話しますんで〉
Ah...I'll call you back later!
（和緒）コユキ君！
Koyuki-kun!
Boss! You want me to get him?
（ゴールディー）
〈ボス！ いいんですか？〉
Hey, do you understand
what you're doing?!
（和緒）ちょっと あんた
分かってんの？
Huh? Understand what?
（コユキ）え？ 何が？
Cripes! This is the chance of a lifetime!
（和緒）もう～！
こんなおいしいビッグチャンス—
It's never going to
come around again!
めったにあるもんじゃないのよ！
ホンットにもう！
-I can't believe this!
-Things are so boring lately.
No one would notice
if I were gone.
（コユキ）竜介… 君…
Ryusuke-kun...
What? Ryusuke Minami
has disappeared?
（レオン）〈何？
リュースケ・ミナミが消えた？〉
（ゴールディー）〈イエス ボス〉
Yeah, Boss.
Find him. And take him out!
（レオン）〈見つけ出して—〉
〈始末しろ〉
Yeah.
（ゴールディー）〈イエス！〉
But I guess we gotta take care
of that kid from yesterday, too, huh?
〈それから
きのうのガキにも—〉
〈しかるべき制裁が
必要かと思いますが…〉
〈やりますか？〉
You want me to put him on his back?
I've never heard that kind of music...
〈ああいう“Don't you
mess with me”も—〉
Like "Don't You Mess with Me."
〈初めて聴いたな〉
W-What'd you say, Boss?
（ゴールディー）
〈え 何ですってボス？〉
（千葉）俺は もう二度と
バンドをやるつもりは ない！
I'll never be part of a band again!
-Huh?! That's...
-Huh!?
（サク）え～！
（コユキ）え～！ そんな…
この店で修業を積んで
行列のできるラーメン屋を目指す！
I'm gonna use this shop
to train myself and learn
with the goal of opening
a chain of ramen shops!
平のヤツも 新しいバンドに
参加したみてえだしな
Taira says he wants
to try a new band, too.
（サク）だけど
このラーメン まずいよ
But this ramen is pretty bad.
ちゃんと修業する店を
選んだほうがいいよ
-You should find
another shop to train at.
-Shut up!
うるせえ！
Please join our group,
Typhoon Stones, as a guitarist!
（センショウ）どうか 我が
台風(たいふう)ストーンズのギターとして—
参加してくれ！
Sorry, but I must refuse.
悪いけど 辞退します
（センショウ）ライブまで
ひとつきあるからさ—
There's a month till
our live performance.
So please think it over. Please!
前向きに考えてみてね
お願い！
じゃあ 頼むぜー！
Really, think about it!
よろしくな！
Please say yes!
（サク）やればいいんじゃ
ないかな？ ヘルプ…
Why won't you join them
to help them out?
Hmm...
コユキ
Koyuki, I wanna talk to you.
話したいことがあるんだ
Huh? Saku...
（コユキ）え… サク！
I'm used to it.
（サク）慣れてるんだけどね
I mean, grade school,
middle school, high school.
なんと 小・中・高 合わせて
５回目だもんね
This will be the fifth time.
But this time is harder than the rest...
changing schools like this.
でも 今回のが 今までで—
一番つらい転校に
なりそうだよ
サク！
Saku!
（サク）まだ２か月も
先の話なんだけどさ
It's still two months away.
真っ先にコユキに
知らせようと思ってね
But I wanted to let you know first.
Saku...
サク…
（サク）そうだ
（コユキ）うん？
Oh yeah...I want to
tell you one more thing.
（サク）コユキに言っとくことが
もう１つあるんだ
（コユキ）何？
What is it?
（サク）こういうことを話すのは
まだ 早いかもしれないけど—
It may be too soon
to bring this up...
But I may quit music after this.
俺は この先 音楽を
やめちゃうかもしれない
けど！ だけど コユキは…
But...
But Koyuki...
You must never quit music!
コユキは
絶対に音楽をやめるな！
サク…
Saku...
「slip(スリップ) out(アウト)」みたいな—
I want you to write more
songs like "Slip Out"...
...that truly moved people's hearts.
人の心をギュッと
つかむような曲を—
いっぱい書いてくれよな！
（コユキ）何 言ってるんだよ！
What're you saying?!
音楽をやめちゃいけないのは
サクだよ！
Saku, you're the one
who mustn't quit music!
俺は お前から
いろんなことを—
I've learned so much...
教わって… きた…
...from you...
（サク）コユキ…
Koyuki...
（センショウ）オーライ！
カモーン！
Hey Tanaka...You were on tonight!
（センショウ）お～ 田中
すげえ イカしてたぜ！
Next time again, 'kay?
（宮沢(みやざわ)）また 頼むよ
カート・コバーン ニッ！
Yeah, I'm amazed.
（ダイゴ）
いや ホント たまげた
See ya!
じゃ また
Huh? Aren't you coming
to the wrap party?
（センショウ）あれ？
打ち上げ 参加しないの？
I was gonna try to convince him...
田中を説得して—
...to be a permanent member
of the Typhoon Stones.
台風ストーンズの正式メンバーに
しようと思ってたのにな
It's been a while,
so I was nervous.
（コユキ）久しぶりだったから
緊張したよ
（サク）
グレイトフルサウンド以来だもんな
Yeah, you haven't played
since Grateful Sound.
Yeah...
I helped out with a band
a couple of times,
（サク）俺も頼まれて
ヘルプで２回出たけど—
but I got nervous, too.
結構 緊張したよ
But...something's missing.
だけど 物足りないんだ
Something's totally missing.
全然 物足りない
'Cuz I really had a taste of it.
改めて実感したんだ
That BECK was a really special band.
BECKって ホントにすごい
バンドだったんだって
（サク）お待たせ！
Sorry to keep you waiting!
It's your last day, Saku...
（真帆）きょうは
サクの最後の日だからさ—
So let's really party up!
パーッといこうぜ！
Yeah!
（真帆）へえ～
サク やるじゃん！
Hey Saku, not bad!
（サク）ヘヘへ…
（益岡）すごーい！
Wow!
Hey Koyuki! Get a strike!
おーい コユキ！
決めろよー！
うっく…
-No way!
-Oh no!
（真帆）えー ウソでしょ？
（コユキ）ああっ ヤベッ！
Yes! Six wins in a row!
（サク）よし！
これで６連勝だ！
（益岡）イェーイ！
Yay!
Hey, let's change teams.
（真帆）
ちょっと組み替えしようよ
私 サクと組みたい
I want to be with Saku!
（コユキ）チクショー！
もう１ゲームやるぞ！
Darn it! One more game!
Huh?!
（益岡）フゥ… ああ
おいしいね ここのラーメン
Isn't their ramen great?
-Really!
-Didn't I tell you?
（サク）ホント！
（コユキ）
でしょ？ でしょ？ ヘヘへ
Okay, on to the next stop!
（真帆）じゃ 次の店 行っくぞー！
Umm...I have curfew, so...
（益岡）あの… 私
そろそろ門限あるんで…
-Huh? So soon?
（コユキ・真帆）えー もう？
（益岡）ゴメンなさい！
I'm sorry!
It's dangerous for a girl alone...
（コユキ）
女の子の１人は危ないから…
Don't worry. I'll see her home.
ああ しっかり送り届けてくる
じゃあな コユキ
So long, Koyuki.
じゃ 元気で
Take care.
-It's kinda sad.
-Yeah...
何か あっけないね
（コユキ）うん…
Chiba-kun is training to be
a ramen shop owner, right?
千葉君はラーメン屋修業でしょ？
平君は 人気インディーズバンドの
ベーシスト
And Taira-kun just joined up with
the popular Indies band as a bassist.
And Ryusuke is missing.
竜介は行方知れず
Seems like BECK is no more.
何か もう
BECKはバラバラだね
う～ さみぃ～
Brrr...cold!
Are you all right?
You sound kinda nasal.
（コユキ）大丈夫？
ちょっと鼻声になってるぞ
じゃあね コユキ
See you around, Koyuki.
Don't catch cold!
（コユキ）風邪ひくなよ
ん… 真帆？
Huh? Maho?
サク！
Saku!
（サク）すっごく 外 寒いよ
It's soo cold outside!
（コユキ）
予報じゃ あした 雪だってさ
The weather forecast
calls for snow tomorrow.
（サク）なるほど！
Oh yeah?
さ 食べようぜ
-Let's eat.
-Yeah.
うわっ ポテチ！
え… キムチ味かよ
Oh! Potato chips! Ew!
Kimchi flavored!?
（コユキ）え… それじゃ
きょうも送っていっただけなの？
So tonight, too, you just
walked her home and that's all?
（サク）残念ながら
手すら つないだことないんだ
Unfortunately, we've never
even held hands.
（コユキ）ふ～ん
Hmm...
（サク）コユキは真帆と
どこまで？
How far have you gone with Maho?
（コユキ）え 俺は その…
Huh? I...
前にサクに話したじゃん
I told you before...
（サク）それじゃ—
Then there's been no progress
since the day of Grateful Sound?
グレイトフルサウンドから
進展なしか？
Hey...let's stop!
This was our first live!
ちょ… ちょ…
ちょっとやめようよ
初ライブじゃん これ！
（サク）うわっ…
恐ろしく ひどいね
Man, it sounds awful!
（コユキ）でさ あの時
千葉君が勘違いしてさ
Remember, Chiba-kun was under
the wrong impression...
（サク）勘違いして
マウントパンチ！
And he got it!
（サク）さて… と
（コユキ）サク…
-Oh well...
-Saku...
（サク）じゃあ そろそろ行くよ
I'm gonna go.
（コユキ）俺 送るよ
（サク）ああ
-I'll walk with you.
-Okay.
-Hey Koyuki...
-Yeah?
おい コユキ！
Huh?!
（サク）雪だ
It's snowing!
（サク）寒いね～
It's freezing!
（コユキ）さむ～
Cold!
（サク）さみぃ～
Cold!!
（コユキ）マジ さみぃ～
Damn, it's cold!
（サク）さみぃぞ こりゃ
It's so cold!
（コユキ）
おんどりゃ さみぃ～ うう～！
Cold!
-Cold!
（サク）さみ…
（コユキ）さみぃ～ ああ…
（サク）じゃあな コユキ
Well good-bye, Koyuki.
Take care, Saku.
（コユキ）元気でな サク
バイトして
１人暮らしのための金をためる
I'll find a part-time job and save
enough money to live on my own.
親を説得して
春には戻ってくるよ
I'll convince my parents
and come back in the spring.
オリジナルメンバーで
BECKを復活させるために—
In order to revive BECK
with the original members...
即 学校辞めて戻ってくる
I'll quit school and come back!
Uh-huh.
元気で！
Take care!
（コユキ）サクも！
You too, Saku!
（サク）すごい渋い選曲だったよ
（コユキ）君は？
That was a great piece.
What's your name?
（サク）３年２組 桜井裕志
-Yuji Sakurai -a senior in Group 2.
-You're...
（コユキ）うわっ その顔！
（サク）これを渡したくてさ
I wanted to give this to you.
It's the Dying Breed's
live concert in Germany.
ダイブリのドイツでのライブなんだ
田中君は—
Did you read the interview
of Eddy Lee in Guitar World?
「ギターワールド」のエディ・リーの
インタビュー記事 読んだ？
“世の中には２種類の人間がいる”
There are two types
of people in this world.
“賢い人間と素直な人間だ”
Clever people and obedient people.
“賢い人間は誰かの作った
規律と道徳が—”
Clever people think that the world moves
because of laws and morals created by man.
“世界を動かす
すべてだと思っている”
They think it's everything.
“だが 俺は そんなもん
へとも思っちゃいない”
But I don't bother with any of that.
さすがエディだよね
Isn't Eddy amazing?
へぇー
田中君 バンドやってるんだ
So, you're in a band?
（男性）お～っと
フンッ
コユキ！ フッ
Koyuki!
（男性）お～っととと…
Full moon sways
Gently in the night of one fine day
What a fool
I don't know 'bout tomorrow
What it's like to be
Ah...
I was fool
Couldn't let myself to go
Even though I feel
The end
Full moon sways
Smiling in my arms for all those years
Next week: 'America'
（千葉）次週「アメリカ」
俺たちの旅は続く
Our journey continues.
俺の予告は
おしまいだけどな
Although it's the end
of my ramen shop.